Eric Constantinides

eric@ericconstantinides.com San Jose, CA (415) 571-6764







Intro

In a nutshell: I'm am a MERN Stack (Mongo, Express, React, Node) developer specializing in React, Redux, ES2015/ES6, Sass, and Vanilla JS.

Previously: I was Lead Front-End Developer at EverSport Media, responsible for the consumer-facing and administration themes of eversport.tv as well as the front-end for their Single Page App. Before EverSport, I was Senior Web Developer at Flickerbox in San Francisco, creating enterprise-level websites.

Most Recently: After my last company (EverSport) collapsed, I pivoted my career towards React and the MERN stack.

Experience

EverSport Media Online Video Provider in Los Gatos, CA

Sep. 2015 - Jan. 2017

Lead Front-end Developer: Created and updated EverSport's custom themes and modules using PHP, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Designed and developed the site as well as the user-interface for the embeddable JavaScript content and video player to run on 3rd party sites.

- EverSport.tv (2015–2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass, PHP
- Single Page App (2015-2017) Lead Front-End Developer, Co-Designer, JavaScript, JSON, AJAX, Sass
- EverSport.tv Admin Theme (2015-2017) Lead Theme Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass, PHP

Flickerbox, Inc. Agency in San Francisco, CA

Jan, 2012 - June, 2015

Senior LAMP Stack Web Developer (Jan, 2014 - June, 2015): Additional duties included orchestrating the weekly developer meetings; drafting timelines and estimates for future projects; composing technical briefs for client-side contracts.

LAMP Stack Web Developer (Jan, 2012 - Jan, 2014): Architected content structure for websites. Hand-coded HTML, SCSS (CSS), and JS from designer's PSD files into responsive and interactive web pages. Implemented JavaScript libraries and wrote custom JavaScript/jQuery code.

- PureStorage.com (2015) Lead Developer, Static HTML, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress
- Adallom.com (2015) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Platfora.com (2014) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Alteryx.com (2014) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Okta.com (2014) Lead Developer, PHP, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress

- Abaxis.com/veterinary (2013) Lead Developer, JavaScript, Sass, WordPress
- SocialChorus.com (2013) Lead Developer, WordPress CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- <u>Pentaho.com</u> (2013) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- LiveOps.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, CSS
- IslandResortCasino.com (2012) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, CSS

Full Stack Web Developer: Set up sites using a Virtual Private Server (Digital Ocean). Transform mock-ups into HTML templates. Code CSS, HTML, and JavaScript. Host and manage sites.

- <u>ConstantlyBeing.com</u> (2017)
 <u>Lead Developer, Co-Designer</u>, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- Annachich.com (2016)
 Lead Developer, Co-Designer, Drupal, Drupal Commerce, JavaScript, Sass
- <u>PaoloShoes.com</u> (2015)
 <u>Lead Developer, Co-Designer</u>, Drupal CMS, UberCart, JavaScript, Sass
- <u>CameronVail.com</u> (2016)
 <u>Lead Developer</u>, Drupal CMS, JavaScript, Sass
- <u>DukeDuchess.com</u> (2011)
 <u>Lead Developer</u>, Drupal CMS, Ubercart, JavaScript, CSS

- YouCanBikeThere.com (2011) Lead Developer, Drupal CMS, CSS
- <u>BottomlessBrunch.com</u> (2011)
 <u>Lead Developer</u>, Drupal CMS, CSS
- <u>ChicFashion.com</u> (2010)
 <u>Lead Developer</u>, Drupal CMS, CSS
- <u>BayAreaBikes.org</u> (2008)
 <u>Lead Developer</u> | <u>Lead Designer</u>, Drupal CMS, CSS

Skills

Primary Skills My main area of concentration

- React, JSX, Redux, Create-React-App
- JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, ES2015 / ES6
- Node, Express, mongoDB, npm / yarn
- JS Tools, Gulp, Webpack, Babel

- CSS, Sass/SCSS, BEM CSS, FlexBox
- HTML. HTML5
- Git, GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree
- User Experience (UX), Responsive Design, User Interface (UI)

Supplementary Skills Important proficiencies that aren't my primary focus

- Design Apps, PhotoShop, Illustrator
- Front-end helpers, jQuery, Bootstrap
- PHP, SQL, MySQL
- CMS Theming, Drupal (advanced), WordPress
- Online Tools, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Jira
- Marketing Automation, Eloqua, Salesforce, Marketo
- Cloud Hosting, Acquia, Amazon Web Services, DigitalOcean VPS
- Code Editing, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, Chrome Developer Tools
- Apache, Unix, HTTPS/SSL

Education

W.P. Carey School of Business in Tempe, AZ

Arizona State University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems (CIS): 3.75 Computer Information Systems GPA **Bachelor of Science, Marketing:** 4.0 Marketing GPA